# COREY HAWTHORNE

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER





https://github.com/chawthorne02



**4** 864-293-0404

#### SUMMARY

Former educator transitioning into Front End Developer role after completing Carolina Code School. I have experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, BootStrap, React, Python, Django, React BootStrap, Rest API'S and I understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code with experience in Agile methodology.

### **Skills**

Coding languages - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Frameworks - React, Django, Django Rest Framework, BootStrap, Rest API'S, Git, Github

Other tools - Material UI, React Bootstrap, Framer Motion, React Router, JS Cookies, Microsoft Office

### **Projects**

 Created an app where users are able to find and connect with a certified tutor for a personalized learning plan.

**Better Minds Tutoring App** 

- Implemented JS Cookies where user data is stored
- Managed accounts in the rest API'S on the backend using Django rest Framework
- Accounts are stored in database using Django models and SQL Lite
- Used React for user interface and React Router to navigate through site
- Used Send Grid Email API to notify tutor of a new student that has selected them
- Implemented Material UI for front-end design on ratings left by students on tutors
- Used React Bootstrap for card design for the tutors and students
- Used HTML and CSS is used for structural and visual layout of the site

https://www.loom.com/share/4074ed81e442409a9e3183c9e073c0cat

Pixel Perfect

- Created UI with pixels implementing the same design on screen
- Used HTML and CSS for structural and visual design of the site
- Made UI responsive to other devices

## **Employment**

Aug. 2021 to June 2022

Teacher - Bethel Elementary School - Mauldin SC

- Implemented classroom management improvements to enhance class morale and engagement
- Drove student learning by establishing clear classroom plans and group objectives as well as actionable strategies to achieve each goal
- Helped students develop self-esteem and life skills by fostering healthy conflict resolution, critical thinking, and communication

June. 2009 to July 2021

Host - Ihop - Greenville SC

- Monitored front entrance for new guest while assisting servers by taking and delivering drink orders
- Cultivated positive guest relations by managing information and orchestrating speedy
- Watched dining area staff to evaluate server loads and calculate accurate wait times

#### **Education**

Aug 2022 - Nov 2022

Carolina Code School - Greenville SC

• Web Development Immersive Certification

Aug 2014 - May 2019

University of South Carolina - Columbia SC

- Bachelors of Arts in Elementary Education w/ minor in Counseling
- GPA 3.6